let questions=[
    {
        num:1,
        question:"What does HTML stand for?",
        answer:"Hyper Text Markup Language",
        options:[
            "Hyper Text Markup Language",
            "Hyperlinks and Text Markup Language",
            "Home Text Multiple Language",
        "High Tech Markup Language"
        ]
    },
    {
        num:2,
        question:"Which HTML element is used to define a section of a document that is intended for navigation links?",
        answer:"nav",
        options:[
            "header",
            "nav",
            "section",
            "footer"
        ]
    },
    {
        num:3,
        question:"In CSS, which selector has the highest specificity?",
        answer:"ID selector",
        options:[
            "ID selector",
            "Class selector",
            "Element selector",
            "Universal selector"
        ]
    },
    {
        num:4,
        question:"Which JavaScript keyword is used for declaring a variable that can be reassigned but is block-scoped?",
        answer:"let",
        options:[
            "var",
            "const",
            "let",
            "static"
             ]
    },
    {
        num:5,
        question:"What are the four components of the CSS Box Model, from the innermost to the outermost?",
        answer:"Content, Padding, Border, Margin ",
        options:[
            "Content, Padding, Margin, Border",
            "Content, Padding, Border, Margin ",
            "Margin, Border, Padding, Content",
            "Border, Content, Padding, Margin"
             ]
    },
    {
        num:6,
        question:"Which HTTP status code indicates that the request has succeeded and a new resource has been created as a result?",
        answer:"201 Created",
        options:[
            " 200 OK",
            "201 Created",
            "301 Moved Permanently",
            "400 Bad Request"
             ]
    },
  {
        num:7,
        question:"What is the primary purpose of the `alt` attribute in an HTML `<img>` tag?",
        answer:"To display text if the image fails to load and for screen readers.",
        options:[
            "To provide a caption that appears below the image.",
            "To display text if the image fails to load and for screen readers.",
            "To define the image's dimensions (height and width).",
            "To provide a tooltip that appears when the user hovers over the image."
            
        ]
    },
    {
        num:8,
        question:"In a Flexbox container, which property is used to align flex items along the main-axis?",
        answer:"justify-content",
        options:[
            "align-items",
            "flex-direction",
            "justify-content",
            "align-content"
            ]
    },
    {
        num:9,
        question:"What does SEO stands for?",
        answer:"Search Engine Optimization",
        options:[
            "Search Engine Option",
            "Style Embedded Option",
            "Structured Engine Option",
            "Search Engine Optimization"
             ]
    },
    {
        num:10,
        question:"What does CSS stands for?",
        answer:"Cascade Style Sheet",
        options:[
            "Computer Screen Server",
            "Cascade Style Sheet",
            "Contest Style Sheet",
            "Computer Style Screen"
             ]
    },
    {
        num:11,
        question:"Which of the three core web languages is responsible for defining the **structure and content** of a web page?",
        answer:"HTML",
        options:[
            "Python",
            "CSS",
            "HTML",
            "Javascript"
        ]
    },
    {
        num:12,
        question:"Which language is used for styling of the web pages?",
        answer:"CSS",
        options:[
            "CSS",
            "C",
            "C#",
            "C++"
            
        ]
    },
    {
        num:13,
        question:" Code that runs directly in a user's web browser, handling the visual interface and interactivity, is known as:",
        answer:"Front-End Development",
        options:[
            "Database Management",
            "Server-Side Scripting",
            "Back-End Development",
            "Front-End Development"
        ]
    },
    {
        num:14,
        question:" Which of these language is used for interaction to the web page?",
        answer:"Javascript",
        options:[
            "HTML",
            "Javascript",
            "Python",
            "CSS"
        ]
    },
    {
        num:15,
        question:" A developer who is proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript (React), Python (Django), and SQL is typically referred to as a:",
        answer:"Full-Stack Developer",
        options:[
            "DevOps Engineer",
            "Web Designer",
            "Full-Stack Developer",
            "Front-End Specialist"
        ]
    }
];
